Adam Che

AdamC.co | (719) 357-5617 | adamactual.io@gmail.com | Yorba Linda CA

BUSINESS INFORMATION SYSTEMS PROFESSIONAL

Seven years of experience in hardware support, web development, requirements gathering, testing, and test development. Solid business management skills with the ability to analyze needs, forecast goals, and implement new diverse concepts. Produce and analyze project data for forecasting, trending, results analysis, and reporting. Ability to establish and lead cooperative and effective working relationships with individuals at all levels of the organization. Combination of strong analytical and problem-solving skills, detail oriented and highly organized. Seek process improvement to help everyone on the team do better work. Look for learning opportunities in every task and interaction, no matter how big or small.

EDUCATION

- UCI, 2016 | Certification, Mobile Application Development
- CSUF, 2008 | BA, Information Systems Decision Science

TECHNOLOGIES

- Git, Team Foundation Version Control
- C#, VB.Net, ASP.Net, T-SQL
- MVC, HTML 5, CSS 3, Bootstrap
 - o Learning MEAN stack
- Unity 3D, Maya, Blender,
- Facebook and Google API's

- Test Driven Development, QA Testing
- Project Management: MS Project 2012
- User Interaction, Requirements gathering
- Windows Administration: IIS 8.x, Hyper-V, Firewall, DNS, DHCP, Active Directory

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Mathematics Tutor Specialist, Orange County Department of Education, 07/2014 - Present

- Counsel students to improve performance and develop problem solving skills.
- Teach and remediate procedural skill in mathematics including linear and geometric algebra.
- Teach programming concepts in software engineering (Python/C#) and web development (HTML/CSS/JavaScript).

Software Engineer (Jr.), SubScience Studios, 07/2011 – 07/2014 PROJECT MANAGEMENT

- Delivered project plans and scopes for IT Projects worth \$1.2 million in revenue.
- Integrated Microsoft Project 2013 for improved reporting.
- Structured and performed queries in a data warehouse to monitor metrics (T-SQL). Worked with Kontagent mobile analytics.
- Created project budget and analysis reports; designed metrics and KPIs for mobile applications.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

- Reduced page load times, removed redundant CSS, consolidated JavaScript libraries, fixed, documented, and tested code.
- Wrote unit tests in C# in Microsoft Test Manager to pull/push data from SQL Server.
- Created responsive Views (Visual Studio TFS 2012, MVC 4, C#, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, jQuery).
- Wrote simple Controller methods to pass JSON data to View from Entity Framework LINQ queries in Model.
- Contributing C# programmer on Physics, Animation, and Camera Controllers.

SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATION

- Installed, configured, and maintained the following technologies:
 - o Virtual private network (VPN) with windows server 2012.
 - o Virtualized servers on Amazon Web Services (AWS) and Windows Server 2008.
 - o Google Aps for Business.
 - o Apple and Android developer and merchant accounts.
 - o Unity3D game engine for asset sharing through AWS EC2.

Adam Che

AdamC.co | (719) 357-5617 | adamactual.io@gmail.com | Yorba Linda CA

IT Specialist, Civica Software, 01/2009 - 06/2011

- Provided remote and on-site Tier I and Tier 2 support to clients running proprietary ALPR system.
- Created reporting tools in VB.NET, C#. SQL.
- Organized inter-agency meetings, scheduled resources for code deployment, and assisted with the migration of build changes across application environments.
- Designed and implemented training programs to facilitate organizational development in ALPR integration saving a total of \$90,000 over 30 projects.
- Administered Windows Server 2008 including Active Directory and Exchange Server.
- Installed and configured Windows Embedded XP/7 Operating Systems.
- Translated business process and requirements into systems requirements and worked with senior programmers to address customer needs.
- Authored technical documentation for system maintenance, user support, and training of information systems.
- Front-end web development (ASP.NET, VB.NET, HTML, CSS, JavaScript) for local government agencies including Irvine, Palo Alto, Rancho Santa Margarita, Laguna Beach, and Conejo Recreation and Park District.

IT Specialist (Internship), U.S. Department of Defense, 2004 – 2008

- Designed network diagrams, performed RF site surveys for Quality of Service (QoS).
- Authored RFPs and vendor contracts, selected vendors, and monitored work for contract compliance.
- Diagnosed and resolved issues with hardware and software; Managed help desk requests through Remedy Service Ticket Tracking System.
- Administered Windows Server 2005/2008, managed Active Directory and Exchange Server user accounts.
- Enforced policy regulating user privileges under AR 25-1 and ensured network systems security according to AR 380-19.
- Performed Information Systems Security Monitoring in accordance with AR 380-53.
- Provided analyses of Information Security opportunities/risks.
- TCP/IP Network Administration; deployed, tested, and documented IP-based network devices.
- Installed and configured Windows XP/Vista and Mac OS 10.3/4/5.
- Administered client systems including printers and other peripheral devices.
- Performed imaging of Windows computers using Norton Ghost.
- Developed wireless network installation plans; installed a multi-node wireless network across 15 geographically separated structures.
- Configured and installed Digital Subscriber Line Access Multiplexers (DSLAM), servers, hubs, bridges, switches, and routers.